Finding Aid for School of Music, Theatre & Dance (University of Michigan) publications, 1885-ongoing
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
School of Music, Theatre & Dance (University of Michigan) publications
1885-[ongoing]
1885-1985
University of Michigan. School of Music, Theatre & Dance.
0356 Bimu C321 2
Includes miscellaneous newsletters, bulletins, programs, brochures, articles, calendars, histories, and posters produced by or for the University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre & Dance
6 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group has been transferred in a number of accessions (donor # 5155 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The School of Music records are open without restriction.
For historical note, please consult finding aid for
School of Music (University) records
.
The School of Music, Theatre & Dance Publications are divided into five series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, Topical Publications, Audio Recordings, and Archived Website.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Summer Session.; Ann Arbor School of Music.; University School of Music.
Contributors:
Ann Arbor School of Music.; University School of Music.
Genre/Form:
Bulletins.; Programs.; Brochures.; Articles.; Posters.; Calendars.; Histories.; Newsletters.; Catalogs, College.; Websites.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications document activities of the earlier University School of Music and the present University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre & Dance. Much of the documentation consists of Bulletins of both schools, informing current and prospective students of course offerings. Program Degree Requirements are contained within the Student Handbook for the years dating from 1997 to 2005. There are also program files of concerts and recitals by both students and faculty, music-related conferences and theatrical productions. Contained in the files is an almost complete run of programs from 1885 to 1963. The calendars A Tempo and Music at Michigan give schedules of concerts and performances. The newsletter, Music at Michigan, contains information on happenings within the school including information on faculty, students, and fundraising.
  - Admissions
    - General Information about Graduate Programs, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
    - University Division at Interlochen, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Announcements
    - Guidelines for Students (Non-Music Majors) Electing Performance Instruction in the School of Music, undated (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Articles
    - Miscellaneous, 1912; 1954
      - School of Music Studies nos. 1-4, 1946-1961 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Composition, Music History/Musicology, Music Theory, circa, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Dedication of the School of Music Building, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1951-2005, undated (Box 1)
      - 1946, 1962-1977, 1994 regarding elementary, junior and high school music training (Box 1)
      - Circa 1962, 1982-1983 regarding the Graduate Programs (Box 1)
      - And undated, regarding undergraduate program and admission, circa 1997 (Box 1)
    - Music, 1964-1973 (Box 1)
    - Music and Dance, 1979-1991 (Box 1)
    - Music at Michigan (includes faculty biographical notes), 1980; circa 1985-1987; 1992 (Box 1)
    - Music Education, 1956-1976 (Box 1)
    - Music History and Musicology, 1971; undated (Box 1)
    - Summer Session, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Theater Productions
      - The Power Series, 1985-2000; 2008-2012 (Box 1)
      - The School of Music Season, 1990-2000 (Box 1)
    - Undergraduate Programs, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Walgreen Drama Center -- The Arthur Miller Theatre, undated (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Abridged Announcement, 1934-1945 (Box 1)
    - Announcements of the Ann Arbor School of Music, 1880-1889 (Box 1)
    - Announcements of the University School of Music
      - 1892-1894 (Box 1)
      - 1907-1913 (Box 1)
    - Calendars of the University School of Music
      - 1893-1917, 9 folders (Box 1)
      - 1923-1929, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Elections Across Fields, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
    - School of Music Announcement (Box 2)
      - 1929-1953, 10 folders (Box 2)
      - 1955-1963, 4 folders (Box 2)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 2)
      - 1967-1987, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - School of Music Graduate Bulletin, 1986-1997; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Master of Music and Specialist in Music Programs, 1987-1997, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - School of Music Student Handbook for Graduate and Undergraduates (includes Program Degree Requirements)
      - 1997-2003, 6 folders (Box 2)
      - 2004-2011, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - School of Music Undergraduate Bulletin
      - 1987-1997, 5 folders (Box 3)
    - University School of Music, Department of Piano and Organ Tuning and Repair, 1908-1909 (Box 3)
  - Calendars
    - a Tempo, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
    - Calendar of Events, 1999-2012 (Box 3)
    - Coming Events in the School of Music, 1951-1999; 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Music at Michigan, 1989-2002; 9 folders (Box 3)
    - School of Music Season, 2000-2012 (Box 3)
  - Directories
    - Faculty Listing, 1993-1997 (Box 3)
    - Faculty and Staff Directory, 1996-1996 (Box 3)
    - Personal Sketches of Members of the Faculty of the University School of Music, 1898 (Box 3)
    - Student Listing, 1908-1909 (Box 3)
  - Flyers
    - &, 1988-2008; undated (Box 3)
  - Handbooks
    - Class Piano Handbook, 1994/95 (Box 3)
    - Faculty Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1986-1991 (Box 3)
    - Rackham Students in Music, Dance or Theatre, 1996/97 (Box 3)
    - Teacher Handbook for Piano Pedagogy Laboratory Program, 1994/95 (Box 3)
  - Histories
    - 100 Years of Music at Michigan, 1880-1980, 1979 (Box 3)
    - The School of Music of the University of Michigan, Charles A. Sink, 1931 (Box 3)
    - William D. Revelli 1935/1960 25 Years of Leadership, circa 1960 (Box 3)
  - Invitations
    - 1948-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Musical Scores
    - University of Michigan Chorus, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters
    - Alumni Newsletter, 1943-1947 (Box 4)
    - Michigan Muse, 2006-2011; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Music at Michigan
      - Vol. 2-39, 1968-2006; 34 folders (Box 4)
    - Newsletter, vol. 2-6, 1957-1964; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan Composers' Forum, 1989 (Box 4)
    - The University School of Music Record (Box 5)
      - Vol.1, no.1-2, 1903 (Box 5)
      - Vol.2, no.1-4, 1903-1904 (Box 5)
      - Vol.3, no.1, 1904 (Box 5)
      - Vol.3, no.2, 1905 (Box 5)
  - Posters
    - 1955-2000 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases
    - 1995-1999, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Programs
    - The American Musicological Society and Society for Music in the Liberal Arts College Annual Meeting, 1954 (Box 5)
    - Announcement of Historical Piano and Violin Sonata Recitals, 1910-1911; 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Baroque Trio, 1970-1980 (Box 5)
    - Chamber Choir, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Chamber Winds and Concert Band, 1982-1985 (Box 5)
    - Choral Union Series, Mischa Elman, 1922 (Box 5)
    - Conferences
      - Conference on Organ Music, 1962-1997 (Box 5)
      - Midwestern Conference on School Vocal and Instrumental Music, 1945-1995; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1997 (Box 5)
      - National Band Conductors Conference, 1949-1965; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Summer Conference on Piano Teaching, 1961-1965 (Box 5)
    - Contemporary Directions Ensemble, 1973-1981 (Box 5)
    - Contemporary Music Festival, 1961-1974 (Box 5)
    - Faculty and Student Recitals and Concerts
      - 3rd-32nd seasons, 1885-1924; 13 folders (Box 5)
        (there were two 22nd seasons and no 23rd season)
      - 1924-1927 (Box 5)
      - 1929-1940 (Box 5)
      - 1942-1945 (Box 5)
      - 1948-1950, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 5)
    - The Faculty Chamber Concerts, 1973-1976 (Box 5)
    - Michigan Youth Symphony, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-2000; undated (Box 5)
    - Musical Theater, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Musical Youth International, 1980-1983 (Box 5)
    - Organ Concerts, 1970-1986; undated (Box 5)
    - Organ by Palmer Christian, 1927-1930 (Box 6)
    - Scholarship Showcase, 2008 (Box 6)
    - School of Music, (Choral Union, May Festival, Twilight Organ, Faculty Concerts, and Student Recitals), 1930-1936 (Box 6)
    - School of Music, (Choral Union, May Festival, Twilight Organ, Faculty Concerts, Student Recitals, and Carillon Recitals), 1936-1941 (Box 6)
    - School of Music, (Organ, Faculty Concerts, Student Recitals, Carillon Recitals, National Music Camp, Choral Union, Chamber Music, May Festival), 1941-1944 (Box 6)
    - School of Music (bound programs) [Located Separately Y 402 2]
      - 1944/45-2011/12 (Box 6)
        (missing 1948/49, 1956/57 1967/68)
    - Stanley Quartet, 1969-1974 (Box 6)
    - Summer Carillon Recital Series, 1974-1996 (Box 6)
    - Summer Session, 1970-1983 (Box 6)
    - Symposia
      - Black American Music Symposium, 1985 (Box 6)
      - Midwest Composers' Symposium, 1983-1989 (Box 6)
      - Unisys African-American Composers Symposium Chamber Concert, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Theatrical
      - Miscellaneous, 1975-1989 (Box 6)
      - Opera Theatre, 1970-1972; 1978-1979; undated (Box 6)
      - Project Theatre, 1988; undated (Box 6)
    - University Philharmonia, 1971-1991 (Box 6)
    - University Symphony Orchestra, 1958-2000 (Box 6)
  - Proposals
    - The Shepherd Wing: An Addition to Revelli Hall, undated (Box 6)
  - Reports
    - Self-Study Report, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Syllabi
    - A Radio Course in the Playing of All Band Instruments, 1931 (Box 6)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Afro-American Music Collection
    - Brochures, undated (Box 6)
    - Newsletters
      - Afro-American Music Collection Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - Black American Composers: A Series of Vocal Music, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Center for Performing Arts and Technology
    - Newsletters
      - Note-On, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Dance Department
    - Brochures, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-1993 (Box 6)
    - Newsletter
      - Dance at Michigan, 1988-1995 (Box 6)
      - Focus on Dance at Michigan, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - Dance Company &, 1980-1999; undated (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous &, 1974-1976; undated (Box 6)
  - Department of Theatre and Drama
    - Brochures
      - Graduate Theatre Programs, circa late, 1980s (Box 6)
      - Graduate Theatre Studies, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
      - Theatre, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Theatre and Drama, undated (Box 6)
      - Theatre Marquee, 1982 (Box 6)
      - Theatre at Michigan
        - BFA in Design, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
        - BFA in Design and Production, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
        - BFA in Performance, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
        - General, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
        - MFA in Design, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
        - MFA and PhD in Theatre Practice, 1997 (Box 6)
      - Undergraduate Programs in Theatre, 1997 (Box 6)
    - Handbooks
      - BFA Performance, 2006-2008 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters
      - Backstage, 2007 (Box 6)
      - Theatre at Michigan
        - 1989-1992 (Box 6)
        - 1993-2009 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - 1993, 2010 (Box 6)
  - Division of Conducting
    - Brochure, not dated (Box 6)
  - Division of Contemporary ARTS
    - Brochure, undated (Box 6)
  - El Mariachi Michicano
    - 1997 (Box 6)
  - Musical Theatre Program
    - Booklets
      - 25th Anniversary (Box 6)
    - Brochures, undated (Box 6)
    - Programs, 1993-2011 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - Honors Assembly, 1961; 1980; 1983 (Box 6)
  - Professional Theatre Program
    - Brochures, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Programs, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Summer Session
    - Bulletin
      - University School of Music, 1909-1910; 1928 (Box 6)
      - School of Music
        - 1930-1935 (Box 6)
        - 1936-1941 (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan Bands
    - Brochures
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6)
      - Symphony Band Tour, 1976; 1982 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - Centennial Celebration, 1997 (Box 6)
      - Symphony Band and Wind Ensemble, 1965-1983 (Box 6)
      - University Band, 1983-1987 (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan Arts Chorale, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Bands, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Bands Present Bandorama, Featuring the Varsity Band, the Symphony Band, the Jazz Band, the Marching Band, 1964-1985; 2011 (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Concert Band, 1940; 1973-1974 (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Jazz Band, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Symphony Band, 1954-1990; undated (Box 6)
      - The University of Michigan Varsity Band, 1962-1974 (Box 6)
- Topical Publications
  - Alumni
    - Directories
      - Class of 1944, Fiftieth Reunion, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Programs
      - Reunions, 1990-1991; 1995; 2006 (Box 6)
  - Development
    - Booklets
      - Capital Campaign for the University of Michigan School of Music, 1983 (Box 6)
      - School of Music Endowed Funds, 2001 (Box 6)
      - Vocal Arts Center and Organ Teaching Studio, undated (Box 6)
    - Brochures
      - &, 1985-1994; undated (Box 6)
    - Reports
      - Giving Report, 2001-2005 (Box 6)
- Audio Recordings
  - Marching Band, Tuba and Euphonium Ensemble, Symphony Band, Jazz Repertory Ensemble, Men's Glee Club, Instruments from the Stearns Collection
    - Fall 1979 Alumni Issue, 33 1/3 RPM soundsheet (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan Jazz, circa late 1960s; 33 1/3 RPM record (Box 6)
- Archived Website
  - Website capture, May 15, 2002 (Box 2)
    (Original URL http://www.music.umich.edu/)
  - Website as of, May 22, 2003; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 3)
  - Archived School of Music home page
  - Archived websites related to the School of Music, 2010-[ongoing]